(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T21:06:46.691241",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
見える？この目の涙が
Can you see the tears in my eyes?
命の色に滲んでいる
Stained in the colors of life...
何を残して与えてくれた？
What did you leave behind and give me?
追いかけて潰れて
Chasing, breaking down...
青と赤と白 混ざる
Blue, red, and white, all mixed together.
この世界の中で叫んでいる
I'm shouting out in this world.
何を求めて歩いてた？
What did you search for and walk towards?
追いかけて疲れて
Chasing, getting tired...
どのくらい異常？
Just how abnormal is this?
壊れているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
Yes, I'm breaking down.
それでも息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to breathe.
君に見えているの？
Can you see it?
見える？ この目の涙
Can you see? Through these tears
命の色に滲んでいる
The colors of life are blurring
何を残して与えた？
What did you leave and give?
問いかけて 壊れて
Calling out, collapsing
青と赤と白 混ざる
Blue, red, and white blurring
この世の中で叫んでいる
Within this world I'm shouting
何を求めて歩いた？
What were you looking for as you walked?
追いかけて 疲れて
Chasing, getting tired
どのくらい 異常？
How abnormal is it?
壊れているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking!
それでも 息を
Even still I want to
したい したい
...keep breathing
君に見えているの？
Can you see it?
夢のように最後の
Like a dream, even the final
言葉も詰まるよ error
words are choked up, error
遠い日のこと
On a distant day
淡い光が空に溢れている
A faint light is filling the sky
何を選んで並べた？
What did you choose and line up?
涙色 重ねて
Overlapping tear colors
浮かぶその 身体
That floating body
意識の中 溶けて滲んでしまう
Melting and blurring in consciousness
与えることも 失うことも
Even giving, even losing
忘れることも できないの？
Even forgetting, can't I do it?
暴れだす この error
Raging, this error
殺して笑う 僕が また error
Killing and laughing, I error again
壊しているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊して知るの？
Do I know by breaking?
それでも 涙
Even still, tears...
痛い 痛い
...hurt, hurt
君に届いたの？
Did it reach you?
歌う声に最後の
Even lining up the last
言葉 並べても
words to my singing voice
重なる 色 滲んで
Overlapping colors blur
壊れているの？
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking!
それでも 息を
Even still I want to
したい したい
...keep breathing
君に見えていたの？
Could you see it?
夢のように最後の
Like a dream, even the final
言葉も詰まるよ error
words are choked up, error
夢のような 最後の言葉も...
Like a dream, even the final words...
はーい！ 皆さんこんばんは！ 改めまして明けましておめでとうございます！
Hi everyone, good evening! Once again, Happy New Year!
1月3日、えっと常闇トワのなんと3周年を迎えることができました！ ありがとう！
On January 3rd... Tokoyami Towa was able to celebrate her 3rd anniversary! Thank you!
ふうー！ どうでしたか？
Whew! How was it?
はい、今歌った曲はですね、あのニキさんのエラーという曲でしたー！
Yes, the song I just sang was '-ERROR' by niki-san!
えー、カバー曲の中でトワがね、投稿した中で一番ね再生されてて、みんなもね結構知ってくれてる曲なんじゃないかなと思っております。ありがとうございます！
Um, among cover songs, this is the one with the most views that I've posted, and I think many of you know it well. Thank you so much!
ふうー！ ありがとう！
Whew! Thank you!
なんかもうすごい拍手と、紫のハートとかもねありがとうね！ 見えてるよー！
And thank you for all the applause and purple hearts! I can see them!
はい、ということで今日はですね、ハッシュタグなんですけれども、常闇トワ3周年記念ライブでつぶやいてください。よろしくね！
Right, so today's hashtag is #TokoyamiTowa3rdAnniversaryLIVE. Please tweet with it, okay?
めざせトレンド1位！ おほほい！
Let's aim for #1 on trending! Ohohoi!
はい、ということでね、えー、本日もっていうことで連発していきたいと思います！
Right, so as I said today, we're going to keep going with consecutive songs!
ははは！ はい、今日の配信タイトルなんですけれども
Hahaha! Now, as for today's stream title,
ミックスツーというタイトルになっておりまして、え、前回生誕祭でミックスというタイトルの、あの配信をやらしていただいたんですけども
it's called 'MIX 2'. Last time for my birthday, I did a stream titled 'MIX',
そん時、あの、そのホロライブメンバーの曲を、そのホロライブメンバーと一緒に歌って踊るということをしたんですね。
where I sang and danced to Hololive member songs together with the Hololive members.
で、そん時ね、いっぱいにね、悩んだんですよ。いっぱい歌いたい曲があって、で、あ、でも時間がってことで
And back then, I struggled a lot. There were so many songs I wanted to sing, but due to time constraints,
まあ、何名かに声をかけさせていただいたんですけども、まだまだ歌いたい曲と、一緒にね踊りたい人とかいっぱいいたので
I only reached out to a few people, but there were still so many songs I wanted to sing and people I wanted to dance with,
え、今回はまた前回とは違うメンバーをお呼びしてやっていきたいと思います！
so this time I invited different members from last time to do it!
イエーイ！ はい、ではね、このあとはねゲストパートになります。えー、本当にね、あの歌もねダンスもねすごい頑張ったので
Yay! Alright, so after this, it'll be the guest part. We worked really hard on both singing and dancing,
楽しいでって見てもらえたらなと思います！ では最後まで楽しんでください！ どうぞ！
so I hope you'll enjoy watching it! Please enjoy it all the way to the end! Here we go!
くらいほうばか見てないで
Don't just look at the dark side,
うらぱぱぱぱらりら踊れよ
Dance to the ura-pa-pa-pararira rhythm!
魔界学校の優等生
The honor student of the demon world school,
華やかなわがままたたえよ
Praise my glamorous selfishness!
いないいないばぁでこっち向いて
Turn over here with a peek-a-boo,
したたかな未来を咲かせよ
And let a clever future bloom!
次第愛まって高まって
Love builds up and rises higher,
溜まったMP放て黒魔術
Release stored MP with dark magic!
底の奥に集えよ
Gather in the depths below,
闇に震えるケルベロス
O Cerberus trembling in the dark!
切実に響く言葉は
The words echoing so earnestly—
ぶっちぎれ破狂パラダイス
Tear through it, madness paradise!
きらり心奥底まで届け
Glittering brightly, reach deep into the heart,
これからも私の元で
Forever by my side from now on!
不思議な力打ち放て
Unleash this mysterious power,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile too!
うらぱぱぱぱらりら歌えば
If we sing the ura-pa-pa-pararira song,
いっしょういっしょうだいよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
クライもんなしかしてないで
Don't just sit there crying,
怠ったからにはさぁ踊れよ
Now that you've idled, come on and dance!
視界外面ずらさないで
Don't look away from my field of view,
今はただ離れてかないで
Right now, just don't leave my side!
いやいや待ってあっち向いて
No, no, wait, look over there!
今はまだ心の準備を
Right now, my heart's still preparing—
期待さえ切って固まって
Cut off expectations and freeze up,
うらぱぱぱぱらりら動け黒魔術
Ura-pa-pa-pararira, move, dark magic!
われに続け今宵の
Follow me into tonight's
闇を破れメシアよ
Darkness, break through, O Messiah!
うつべきものその名は
The one we must strike, its name is
眠りの発祥パラダイス
The genesis paradise of sleep!
きらり心奥底まで届け
Glittering brightly, reach deep into the heart,
白黒つけてあげるから
I'll settle things in black and white for you!
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandishing this mysterious power,
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Making everyone smile along!
うらぱぱぱぱらりら歌えば
If we sing the ura-pa-pa-pararira song,
いっしょういっしょうかものね？
We'll surely be together forever, right?
ひらりひらりと紫に染まって
Fluttering and dyeing in purple,
これからもあなたの元で
Forever by your side from now on,
奇跡の呪文解き放て
Unleash the spell of miracles,
咲かせえる笑顔の花を
And make the flowers of smiling faces bloom!
きらり心奥底まで届け
Glittering brightly, reach deep into the heart,
これからも変わらないままで
Staying unchanged from now on as well!
不思議な力ほら宿って
Look, this mysterious power dwells within,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile too!
うらぱぱぱぱらりら歌えば
If we sing the ura-pa-pa-pararira song,
いっしょういっしょうだよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対いっしょうだよね？
Absolutely together forever, right?
私と take a step yeah
Take a step with me, yeah,
今宵はバラ色 night
Tonight is a rose-colored night.
夢をのせて 踊りましょう
Let's dance, carrying our dreams along!
なんて触れたい
What's this? I want to touch you,
知りたい 隠した想い
I want to know your hidden feelings.
月が綺麗ね ロマンティック
The moon is so lovely, romantic.
時には甘く 熟れた果実のように
Sometimes sweetly, like a ripe fruit,
キミにそっと 囁くの
I whisper softly to you.
情熱の 誘うままに ねぇ
Led by passion, hey—
本当の素顔 見せて
Show me your true face!
もっと give me gimme love!
Give me, gimme love even more!
私の全てを
Give me your all!
だってcrazy in crazy in love
Because I'm crazy in, crazy in love,
本気 魅せてあげる
I'll show you my seriousness!
アブラカタブラ (hey!)
Abracadabra (hey!)
キミと出逢えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you,
アブラカタブラ (hey!)
Abracadabra (hey!)
愛を込めて 踊りましょう
Let's dance with love poured in!
あの日語った夢は
The dream we talked about that day—
キミと出会えた奇跡に
For the miracle of meeting you,
ずっと語った夢は
The dream we kept talking about—
愛を込めて踊りましょう
Let's dance with love poured in!
私と take a step, yeah
Take a step with me, yeah
今宵はバラ色 night
Tonight is a rose-colored night
夢をのせて 踊りましょう (アキローザ！)
Let's carry our dreams and dance (Aki Rosenthal!)
なんだって
No matter what,
触れたい 知り たい 隠した 想い
I want to touch, know, and hide my feelings
月が綺麗ね、ロマンティック
The moon is beautiful, romantic
時には甘く 熟れた果実のように
Sometimes like a sweetly ripened fruit
キミにそっと 囁く の
I gently whisper to you
情熱の誘う ままに
Guided by passion
ほら
Look,
本当の素顔 見せ て
Show me your true face
もっと
More,
give me, gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
私の 全て を
My everything
だって
Because I'm
crazy in, crazy in love
本気 魅せ て あげる
I'll show you my true feelings
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra
キミと出会えた奇跡に
To the miracle of meeting you
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra
愛を込めて 踊りましょう
Let's dance with love
いつだって
Always,
笑って 悩んで 迷う日々 も
Laughing, worrying, and even wandering days
なんて素敵なドラマティック
What a wonderful dramatic
そうやって 探して 感じて 重ね合わせて
Probing, feeling, layering
キミにちょっと 近付く の
Getting a little closer to you
鼓動が叫ぶ くらい
To the point where my heartbeat screams
ほら
Look,
本能で強く 惹かれ て
Strongly attracted by instinct
そう よ
That's right,
give me, gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
溶かして あげるわ
I'll melt you away
きっと
Surely,
fall in, fall in love
need you 止められない の
Need you, I can't stop
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra
こんな素晴らしい世界に
To such a wonderful world
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra
キミのために 踊りましょう
Let's dance for you
もうギリギリで ギリギリな
Already at the limit, at the limit
私のココロ を
My heart
baby キミだけに キミだけ に
Baby, only to you, only to you
全部 届け たいよ
I want to deliver everything
もっと
More,
give me, gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
私の 全て を
My everything
だって
Because I'm
crazy in, crazy in love
本気 魅せ て あげる
I'll show you my true feelings
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra
ネドクター へドクター メンテして オドクター
Net Doctor, health doctor, maintain and dance doctor
またいつもの レイのバグ
Another usual bug of that kind
happy unlucky 生き行きする窓
Happy unlucky, window going back and forth
組み立てて 全マインドシキの心速度
Assemble the heart velocity of all mind systems
私ネオカシネクダラナイで イェイ イェイ
I'm acting crazy, don't be silly, yeah yeah
ワケナイネ ワケナイネ ハジピークなんて
No way, no way, like the start peak
最終セクターのボーイ やらまいかさ
Boy of the final sector, why don't we do it
ドキドキが止まりそネ しまいにって
My heartbeat is about to stop, in the end
リルビネッテユク ヘヴリビデ ネジマヨッテ ネジマヨッテヨ
Little by little going to heaven, wind and get lost
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
ピッポパッポ鳴らして 夢をつくる
Make a dream by ringing pippo pppo
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね デモショ
Just a little bit, just a little bit, but show
飛んだ宇宙じゃ そのうち 頭狂うかも
In the flying universe, my head might go crazy soon
リルビリルビリルビマ
Little by little little by little
ネドクター メンテしたの ドクター
Net Doctor, maintained it, doctor
手加減から 手加減から 抜け出せないならなななな
If we can't escape from holding back
自分 の呪いなんて 笑おう
Let's laugh at our own curses
なんてバカかない おかしない とんでもないね イェイイェイ
How stupid, isn't it funny, no way, yeah yeah
これわモードの だ テクノロジーだ
This is the mode's, it's technology
新幹線くだって メモってるもん
Even taking the Shinkansen, I'm taking notes
わかったら その手ですぐ巻いて
If you understand, wind it up right away with that hand
原則もう笑って ネジマヨッテ ネジマヨッテヨ
Basically laugh already, wind and get lost
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
キミがミステても 笑わせてあげる
Even if you make a mistake, I'll make you laugh
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit
ホラデカルカ なんてかるかる アイデンティティ アップデートして
Look at it lightly, update your identity
止まりがたこころから
From a heart that's hard to stop
リルビ リルビ
Little by little little by little
一切の失態もないのに
Even though there are no failures at all,
はにかんでリリルララ
smiling shyly, liri-lula-la.
その前にひとまずねじ巻いて
Before that, wind it up for now.
リルビなテイクエブリデイでねじ巻いてねじ巻いてよ
Wind it up every day with Rilubi!
ちょっとだけね ちょっとちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit.
拝め夢を作る ちょっとだけね
Worship and make a dream, just a little bit.
ほんのちょっとだけね
Just a tiny little bit.
もう僕でもなんでもいいけど とりあえずちょっとだけ巻いて
Anything is fine, but for now, wind it up just a little.
ちょっとだけね ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit, just a little bit.
こんな険しい道も悪くないよ ちょっとだけね
Even such a rugged path isn't bad, just a little bit.
ちょっとだけね
Just a little bit.
ビルもちょっとだけじゃそのうちでかくなるかも
Even a building might grow big soon if it's just a little.
リルビリルビリルビリルビ...
Rilubi rilubi rilubi...
孤独を並べては みんなフラライヘ
Lining up our loneliness, everyone off to fulleihe.
理屈だなんて ゴミ箱へ
Throwing logic into the trash can.
ミニに覚えあるんでしょ ああ チクチク痛いのね
You remember it well, right? Ah, it hurts with a prickle.
いつしいついの間にかに 裁かれて むしばまれて
Before we knew it, judged and eaten away.
アンレ アンレ 気に傷つけて あくまでも
Unles, unles, hurting your feelings to the bitter end.
癒やしで集まろう おめざめですか
Let's gather for healing, are you awake?
さあ リンドンリンドン 響かせリンドン
Now, ring-dong ring-dong, make it ring, ring-dong!
笑え ハハっと叫べ
Laugh, shout "Ha-ha!"
リンドンリンドン 鳴らせよリンドン
Ring-dong ring-dong, make it sound, ring-dong!
闇が先か 闇の顔が先か
Is the darkness first, or is the dark face first?
噛みつきやしないわ
I won't bite you.
なぐさめもしないわ
I won't even comfort you.
私のものね
You're mine, right?
飽きたらNoDistance
When you get tired of it, NoDistance.
闇にマジで甘いチョコレート溶かしてく
Melting truly sweet chocolate into the darkness.
錆びたクサリ繋いでは砕いてく
Connecting and breaking rusty chains.
狩りの数字あざわぜて瞳を貸してく
Mocking the hunting numbers, lending my eyes.
傷が痛むのね
Your wound hurts, doesn't it?
目がケミズムに踊らされてピシラわれてく
Eyes danced by chemism, being shattered.
アンレ アンレ
Unles, unles.
間違えても正しくなくても 怪しく演じましょ
Whether wrong or right, let's play our roles suspiciously.
あ まだだめですか
Ah, is it still no good?
リンドンリンドン 狂わせリンドン
Ring-dong ring-dong, drive them mad, ring-dong!
最後にハハっと叫べ
Finally, shout "Ha-ha!"
リンドンリンドン 迷わずリンドン
Ring-dong ring-dong, without hesitation, ring-dong!
覚める前に
Before waking up,
告げ得はリンドンリンドン
What you confess is ring-dong ring-dong.
響かせリンドン 笑えハハっと叫べ
Make it ring, ring-dong! Laugh, shout "Ha-ha!"
リンドンリンドン 鳴らせよリンドン 闇が先か 闇の顔が先か
Ring-dong ring-dong, make it sound, ring-dong! Is the darkness first, or is the dark face first?
噛みつきやしないわ
I won't bite you.
なぐさめもしないわ
I won't even comfort you.
私のものね
You're mine, right?
飽きたらNoDistance
When you get tired of it, NoDistance.
太陽が地平線に飲み込まれるのを 眺めていた
I was watching the sun get swallowed by the horizon.
まぶたを閉じれば私をも消してしまえるような気がしたの
It felt like if I closed my eyelids, I could make even myself disappear.
知りたかった
I wanted to know.
くだらないはちゅうじゅうしふうず日常生活 執着を馬鹿になってしまって
Becoming foolish about trivial daily life and attachments...
白む空に 吐き出すため息は
The sighs I exhale into the whitening sky
無色透明で まるでからっぽみたい
Are colorless and transparent, as if completely empty.
ページをめくるば 景色を変えるノベル
As I turn the page, a novel changes the scenery.
カレンダーめくっても 変われもしない僕
Even when I flip the calendar, I remain unchanged.
こするまぶた 満員の電車の中
Rubbing my eyelids inside a crowded train,
まるで誰かの人生のエキストラみたい
I feel like an extra in someone else's life.
ただ欲しかったのは今を生きる理由
All I wanted was a reason to live in the present.
イメージしてた未来にどれだけ近づけたんだろう
How close have I gotten to the future I imagined?
my life いつ日にかカラフル
My life will someday be colorful,
色ののない雨がいつか虹を描くように
Just like colorless rain that will someday paint a rainbow.
my life どんな色のエンドロール
My life, any color of end credits,
涙さえも塗り重ねて描くキャンバス
A canvas painted by layering even tears.
青い願い 挫折の赤い痛み
A blue wish, a red pain of setback.
混ざる色彩はまるでかさぶたみたい
The mixed shades are like a scab.
まばたきも忘れて夢の中にいるんだ
Forgetting even to blink, I'm inside a dream,
何度夜が明けても覚めもしないほど深く
So deep I won't wake no matter how many dawns break.
my life 傷跡さえ隠さず
My life, without even hiding my scars,
胸を締め付ける不安さえ滲ませたっていいさ
Letting the anxiety tightening my chest bleed through.
my life 成れやしないジニアス
My life, a genius I will never become.
だから僕のありのままを描くキャンバス
That's why I paint my true self on this canvas.
どんな僕でいたい
What kind of me do I want to be?
どんな風に生きたい
How do I want to live?
問いかけをパレットに落として探し出した僕の色
I dropped my questions onto the palette for my color.
理想や妄想などいらない 答えはあるわけないさ
I don't need ideals; answers don't exist anyway.
体中をかけるこの思いを今描く
I now paint these feelings running through my body.
my life いつ日の日にかカラフル
My life will someday be colorful,
色ののない雨がいつか虹を描くように
Just like colorless rain that will someday paint a rainbow.
my life どんな色のエンドロール
My life, any color of end credits,
涙さえも塗り重ねて描くキャンバス
A canvas painted by layering even tears.
浅い眠りにたたずんだ
Linger in a shallow sleep,
永遠の終わらせ方を知らないまま
Not knowing how to bring eternity to an end.
巡り合いでは夜行虫
Like night insects drawn to a rendezvous,
水面へと遠く静寂と赤信号
Far away from the water's surface, silence, and red lights.
吐き出そうとしても帰れないどこも
Nowhere to return even if I try to let it out.
私が狂っている
I am going crazy.
かじかんだ身体が離れていく
My numb body drifts away,
なにも感じたくない もう
I don't want to feel anything anymore.
my life いつかの日にかカラフル
My life will someday be colorful,
色ののない雨がいつか虹を描くように 朝焼けでさえ照らしきれないように
Like colorless rain painting a rainbow, unable to be lit by dawn.
暗く 暗く 溺れていく
Darker and darker, I sink away.
なまぬるい永久
A lukewarm eternity...
一度きりの金色の月さえ見失う
Losing sight of even the once-in-a-lifetime golden moon.
染まっては続く夢なら 乾いた太陽を胸に燃えるグリーーム
If this dream continues, I'll burn a dry sun in my chest.
世界が私だけを置いていく
The world leaves only me behind.
はあ 日曜日の朝 気分は少しブルー
Ah, Sunday morning, feeling a little blue.
今週も終わっちゃうな いや困っちゃうな
Another week is ending, oh how troublesome.
やりたいこと山積みだ
So much I want to do piled up high.
そうどうやったって来る月曜日
No matter what, Monday comes around.
きっと囲まれたね鉄格子
Surely surrounded by iron bars,
いつか解き放たれたい 「でも一人じゃ笑えない」
Wanting freedom, "but I can't smile alone."
吹き抜ける風と踊った
I danced with the blowing wind.
ああ 沈む夕日だって
Ah, even the setting sun,
ああ 登る朝日だって
Ah, even the rising sun,
ああ 雨に打たれたって
Ah, even getting beaten by the rain,
そばにいられたら
If I can be by your side.
ループ ループ する毎日が 彩りに溢れてくよ
Every loop of daily life overflows with color.
きっとさんざめく花火の側に 香る夢のように
Beside the sparkling fireworks, like a fragrant dream.
こんな ループ ループ する毎日が かけがえのない宝石のように
Like an irreplaceable jewel, everyday looping on,
いつか大切に思えるのなら
If someday I can cherish it,
週末の夜も愛しいね
Even weekend nights are lovely.
喜怒哀楽 感情の裏の裏に
Behind the emotions of joy and sorrow,
見え隠れしてた 私の合図。
were my glimpses of hidden signals.
君に届いてるのかな
I wonder if they're reaching you...
ああ 春の木陰だって
Ah, even the spring shade,
ああ 夏の日差しだって
ah, even the summer sunlight,
ああ 冬の刹那だって
ah, even the winter's fleeting moment,
秋が来なければ 飽きが来なければ
if autumn doesn't come... if weariness doesn't come...
ループする毎目が 彩りに溢れてくよ
Days that loop and repeat overflow with color.
きっと さんざめく花火の側に 香る夢のように
Surely, like a fragrant dream beside the bustling fireworks.
こんなループする毎日が
Days that loop like this
かけがえない宝石のように
are like irreplaceable jewels.
いつか大切に思えるのなら
If you can someday cherish them,
週末の夜も 金曜の夜も
even weekend nights, Friday nights,
憂鬱な夜も 愛しいね
and even gloomy nights are lovely.
宵の余、良い！
Evening's余, good!
咲き誇んだわちゃわちゃ
Blossoming, bustling-bustling,
今宵は眠れない
tonight we can't sleep!
宵っ張りや遊び尽くせ
Night owls, play your fill,
満面のジャパニーズだ！
with full-faced Japanese style!
積もる溢れてくる苦しむ
Overflowing and piling up, bitter feelings...
すぐる好奇心 十中八九
surpassing curiosity, eight or nine times out of ten
これで決めよ じゃんけんぽいよ
let's decide with this: Rock-paper-scissors!
相子でしょ！
It's a tie!
あっとぱっと開いた
Opening up in a flash,
カレンダーをめくる
turning the calendar pages.
あっとあっと言わせる 花火を打ち上げよう
Let's set off fireworks that will leave everyone speechless!
浮かえ それ見にまわれ
Float up, go see it around,
威勢よき一期のうたげ
a spirited, once-in-a-lifetime banquet!
ざっくざく夜の絵巻なんお庭にはうち
Crunching through the night's picture scroll in our garden,
歌え それ真似ならえ 盆踊り
Sing, imitate that, Bon odori dance,
それすらも愛嬌
even that is charming!
ざっくざく月まで カレンダーお庭にはうち
Crunching all the way to the moon, calendar in our garden!
目を閉じ 目をつむって 一息入れちゃって
Close your eyes, shut your eyes, take a breather,
耳が味あわた軽 いしだだだ
tasting with your ears, light and bouncy!
眠り終わりたくない 何して遊ぼうか
I don't want sleep to end, what should we play next?
暗中模索 ここで決めよ じゃんけんぽいよ
Groping in the dark, let's decide here: Rock-paper-scissors!
相子でしょ！ グーとグーで
It's a tie! Rock and rock,
転んで あいこでしょ！
tumbling down, it's a tie!
あと あとわく ほどざいこう うちなるさ
Afterwards, overflowing to our hearts' content, our inner selves...
泣いて 笑うように続け
Keep crying and laughing,
キラキラのしずくが 掲げ
hoisting up sparkling droplets!
さあ おいでおぼめ寄せる カレンダーお庭にはうち
Come on, gathering up the calendar in our garden,
泣いて 笑いまいすすめる 奇跡のためでもよいぞ
crying, laughing, moving forward, even for the sake of miracles is fine!
さあ おいであふれよ カレンダーお庭にはうち
Come on, overflowing, calendar in our garden!
ああ 北から南 夜を照らす 眩しき光に 連れられて
Ah, from north to south, guided by the dazzling light illuminating the night,
あなたと最高段階にまた 変身 頑張りよよよ
with you to the highest level, transforming once again, do your best!
どうか最終年 おめでとう！
May your final year be blessed, congratulations!
夜の街 迷いし 穂むらの乱歩
Lost in the streets at night, unsteady footsteps
何処から来たのよ 見窄らしいね
Where did you come from? You look so ragged.
ねぇ お家に置いて 温めてあげるよ
Hey, come inside, I'll warm you up.
今までよく頑張ったね
You've tried so hard until now.
ここらで休んでみませんか
How about resting here for a bit?
ゆっくり話をしませんか
How about taking our time to talk?
足跡は雪が消していた
The footprints had been erased by the snow.
声はひどく痛んだ
Your voice was terribly sore.
乾いた 乾いた
Thirsty, thirsty...
遠くの狐がこんこんと 僕たちを探しているようだ
The far-off fox is howling, searching for us.
そっと息を潜めた
Quietly holding my breath.
このままこのまま行こうか 凍てつく雪の中で
Just like this, let's keep going into the freezing snow.
確かな熱を帯びた
Embracing a definite warmth.
呼吸をして声を焼いて 燃えた燃えた竈の火
Breathing and burning our voices, the fire burns bright.
さぁ縁の坦根を超えて 貴方をもっと知りたい
Now, crossing the fences of fate, I want to know you more.
言えないままで 言えないままで
Without being able to say it, without being able to say it...
いつの間にやら雪は雨になりました
Before I knew it, the snow had turned to rain.
夜明け前貴方は早々に此処から出て行ってしまった
Before dawn, you hastily left this place behind.
あんなに泣いていたのに
Even though you were crying so much...
溢れた 溢れた
Overflowing, overflowing...
今までありがとうなんて言わないでよ 置かないでかないで
Don't say "thank you for everything," don't leave me behind.
きっと帰還しない このままこのまま
Surely you won't return, just like this...
いつか夢で会えても貴方にゃきっと届かない
Even if we meet in a dream, it won't reach you.
僕は此処で 僕は此処で
I am right here, I am right here,
袖を濡らしながら帰りを待つだけ
Just waiting for your return while wetting my sleeves.
さぁ宴のたけなわ超えて 生きてみようか今更
Now, surpassing the height of the banquet, shall I try to live?
竈の火は 竈の火は 雨に雨に濡れていた
The fire of purification was soaked in the rain.
晴れた晴れた朝ぼけに 見てるのかな
I wonder if you are watching the clear morning glow.
キラキラの太陽が ワクワクが待ちきれない
The glittering sun is here, I can't wait anymore!
熱い夏が来い！ 恋せよ乙女 連鎖反応！
Bring on the hot summer! Maiden in love, chain reaction!
青い空と白い雲が 心のボルテージ上げていく
The blue sky and white clouds raise the voltage in my heart.
紺色のTシャツまで 今年一番のレコメンド
Even my navy T-shirt is this year's top recommendation!
走り出した海岸線 どこまでだって行けそうだね
Running along the coastline, it feels like we can go anywhere.
数え切れない夏の思い出 君も一緒にいこう
Countless summer memories, let's go together too!
あっという間に進んでく時計 短すぎじゃない？ My summer time!
The clock ticks away in a flash. Isn't it too short? My summer time!
全部最後のメモリーやる気にして 強い風 みんな連れて行け！
Make every last memory count, strong wind, take everyone along!
素晴らしい最良のオーガスタ サンセットの海でジャンプ！はじける汗
Wonderful, best augusta, jump in the sunset sea, splashing sweat!
宝石みたいにキラキラ 眩しく輝け
Shining dazzlingly like precious jewels.
キラキラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです
The glittering sun is full of excitement!
熱い夏が来い！ 恋せよ乙女 連鎖反応！
Bring on the hot summer! Maiden in love, chain reaction!
涼しい風で寝転がって 伸び伸びビーチお昼寝もいいよ
Lying down in the cool breeze, a relaxing beach nap is nice too.
夢の中は何だってできちゃうから いいよね
Anything can happen in a dream, right?
準備OK？ みんな連れてけ！
Ready? Take everyone along!
素晴らしいサイオウガ サンスーセノでジャンプ！はじける汗
Wonderful... jump in the sea, splashing sweat!
ほらキミと二人でキラキラ 眩しく輝け
Look, sparkling brightly together with you.
キラキラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです
The glittering sun is full of excitement!
熱い夏が来い！ これもやろう 連鎖反応！
Bring on the hot summer! Let's do this too, chain reaction!
涼しい風 猫の家で のびのびいてほしいの
Cool breeze, I want you to relax freely at the cat's house.
夢の中は何だってできちゃうから いいよね
Anything is possible in dreams, isn't it?
準備OK？ 準備をしよう！
Ready? Let's get prepared!
キラキラ光るよ スーパースター
Shining brightly, a superstar!
流星宝石を見つけにさ 夜更かしだって平気だよ
To find shooting star jewels, staying up late is no problem!
願いごと 溢れそうな時は 見上げる上にダイビング
When your wishes are overflowing, dive into the sky above!
みんな大好き！
Everyone I love!
ちょっとくらい疲れても平気 みんながくれるファイトがある
Even if we get a little tired, it's fine, everyone gives us fighting spirit!
どこまでだって駆け抜けでいけるから
Because we can dash through to wherever we want!
いいよね 準備をしよう！
Sounds good, let's get ready!
空の果てまで飛んでこう 新しい景色を届けちゃうよ
Let's fly to the edge of the sky, delivering new scenery to you!
眩しく輝け スーパースター
Shining dazzlingly, a superstar!
流星宝石を見つけにさ 夜更かしだって平気だよ
To find shooting star jewels, staying up late is no problem!
一つ一つが 全部全部が
Every single thing, every single one
届いてるから上を向いて
Is reaching us, so look up to the sky!
体中に息を吸い込んだなら 叫ぶよ
If you've breathed deep into your body, shout out loud!
みんな大好き！
We love you all!
毎日が君だけのキミの心 照らすよ
Illumination for your heart, every single day!
新しい元気をまるっとお届けしちゃうよ
We'll deliver whole new energy straight to you!
空の果てまで飛んでこう 新しい景色を届けちゃうよ
Let's fly to the edge of the sky and deliver new scenery!
眩しく輝け スーパースター
Shining dazzlingly, a superstar!
流星宝石を見つけにさ 夜更かしだって平気だよ
To find shooting star jewels, staying up late is no problem!
願いごと 溢れそうな時は 見上げる上にダイビング
When your wishes overflow, dive straight into the sky above!
眩しく輝け スーパースター
Shining dazzlingly, a superstar!
静寂に響いてよ my howling
Echo through the silence, my howling
滔々と流れていく風景
The scenery flowing on endlessly,
刹那的な日々の中で
amidst these fleeting days.
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand extended to me so gently
鼓動に浸る微熱の予感
brims with a slight fever of anticipation.
風に逆らう
Defying the wind,
そう生きてきたから
because that's how I've lived,
君に会って気付く
meeting you made me realize
もう独りじゃない
I'm no longer alone.
瞬きは弧を描き 月へ響く
Blinks trace an arc, echoing to the moon.
爪弾く道 金狼の群れ 共に嘆く夜
Plucking paths, packs of golden wolves, a night we lament together.
伝播する想いは心強くする
Feelings that propagate make the heart stronger.
ついておいでよ 後ろに君がいるから
Follow me, because you're right behind me,
私は迷わない 光射す道へ
I won't get lost on the path bathed in light.
無力だから仲間を求め
Seeking companions because we are powerless,
凍えるから火を灯して
lighting a fire because we are freezing.
変化とともに進化していく
Evolving along with change,
この結末は誰も知らない
no one knows how this will end.
君を信じる そう決めているから
I've decided to believe in you,
どんな異常異常も乗り越えられるよ
so I can overcome any abnormality.
この闇に唯一 凛と咲く花
The sole flower blooming valiantly in this darkness.
恐れなのか 憧れなのか 向かい合う夜空
Is it fear or longing? A night sky facing each other.
駆け抜ける私と君が作り出すこの物語
This story created by you and me running across the earth.
単純な未来じゃない
It's not a simple future.
湧き立つ情熱 この声に乗せよう
Let's put our surging passion into this voice.
空飛ぶ羽根なくても手は繋がれたから
Even without wings to fly, our hands were connected,
この運命を選んだ
so I chose this destiny.
連動する遠吠えは静寂に響いて
Synchronized howls echo through the silence,
何度も何度もその絆を確かめた
confirming that bond over and over again.
瞬きは弧を描き 月へ響く
Blinks trace an arc, echoing to the moon.
爪弾く道 金狼の群れ 共に嘆く夜
Plucking paths, packs of golden wolves, a night we lament together.
伝播する想いは心強くする
Feelings that propagate make the heart stronger.
共に行こうよ 隣に君がいるから
Let's go together, because you are by my side,
私は迷わない 光射す道へ
I won't get lost on the path bathed in light.
Listen to my howling...
狼が止まることはない
The wolf will never stop.
見慣れきったドアの先に
Beyond the familiar door,
変わらない微笑み
an unchanging smile.
ふいにギュッと
Suddenly pulling you close...
見慣れきったドアの先に 変わらない微笑み
Beyond the familiar door, an unchanging smile
ふいにギュッと抱き締めたら ほらまた笑顔が咲いたよ
When I suddenly hold you tight, look, smiles bloom once more.
撮り貯めた日常を
Gathering up our captured everyday moments
寄せ書きみたいに集めてさ
like a colorful message board,
さよならは胸にしまって
keeping our goodbyes tucked inside our hearts,
肩を寄せて 飽きるくらい 話そう
hugging our shoulders, talking until we're tired.
限りない思い出 ポケットに詰め込んで
Stuffing endless memories into our pockets,
挫けそうな時も共に支え合える 大切フォトグラフ
supporting each other when we might break. A precious photograph.
遥か 未来の 先へ これからも 一緒だよ
Far beyond the future, we'll be together from now on.
思いきり笑おう 手を繋ぎ 歌おう この 一瞬が いつまでも 大好き
Let's laugh with all our hearts, hold hands, and sing. I will always love this very moment.
立ち止まって落ち込む日もたまにはいいよね
It's alright to stop and feel down sometimes.
わかち合って寄り添えば 涙も思い出に変わる
If we share and lean on each other, even tears turn into memories.
ささやかな幸せは 飾らない毎日の中にあって
Modest happiness resides within our unpretentious days,
ふとした会話や 隣歩く日々の 宝物なんだ
casual chats and days walking side by side are true treasures.
想い出は溢れ 両手じゃ足りないよ 嬉しさも辛さも 共に笑い合える
Memories overflow, more than two hands can hold, sharing both joy and hardship with a smile.
大切フォトグラフ 最高の笑顔にとびっきり幸せを 大好きなみんなへ 少しくすぐったいけど いつもありがとね
Precious photograph! Wishing the greatest smiles and ultimate happiness to everyone I love. It's a bit embarrassing, but thank you always.
遥か 未来の 先へ これからも 一緒だよ
Far beyond the future, we'll be together from now on.
思いきり笑おう 手を繋ぎ 歌おう この 一瞬が いつまでも 大好き
Let's laugh with all our hearts, hold hands, and sing. I will always love this very moment.
はーい戻ってきたかなー
Ha~i, did I make it back?
ドキドキしたー
My heart was pounding!
いつもありがとね みんなありがとー！
Thank you always, everyone, thank you so much!
ということで、えー常闇トワ3周年記念ライブ、えー最高でしたね！
So, um... Tokoyami Towa's 3rd Anniversary Live... um, it was amazing!
声援どこ行った？
Where did your cheers go?
はい、もうね、見てください、もうさっき戻りましたこのステージ。
Right! So, look everyone, we just returned to this stage.
このステージもね、あのー作ってもらいました。あとほらいっぱいわがままを聞いて素敵なステージに仕立てれました。
This stage was also made for us, you see. And they listened to all my selfish requests to make it such a wonderful stage.
ありがとうございます！ありがとう！
Thank you so much! Thank you!
あのね最後までね、今日はね見てほしいんです。なんと素晴らしいことが三つ、四つ？三つ？四つ？ありますんで。
And you know, I want you to watch all the way to the end today. Because there are three... four? Three? Four wonderful things!
では、えー告知させていただきたいと思います！
So, um, I'd like to make an announcement!
まずひとつめこちらポーン！
First one is right here, boom!
えー、常闇トワ3周年記念グッズセットが発売しまーす！
Um, the Tokoyami Towa 3rd Anniversary Goods Set is now on sale!
最高だっ、ありがと！最高！
It's the best! Thank you! The best!
じゃあ、えっと、グッズのね、内容はこちら！ポン。
Now then, let's go over the details...
はい。
And...
えー、この4点になっておりまして、まあ1つは、あの、特典になるんですけれども。
There are four items in total. One of them is a special...
まあ、3点と、え、特典になっております。じゃあ細かい内容を見ていきましょう。
Well, 3 items plus the special item. Let's look at the details!
まず1つ目はこちら！
First item is this!
キャンバスボードになっております！イラストはめろ先生に描いていただきました！
It's a canvas board! Illustrated by Mero-sensei!
映画の一部みたいじゃない？これ。
Doesn't it look like a scene from a movie?
すごくない？みんな。ポニーテールかわいいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing, everyone? Look at the pony! Isn't it cute?
かわいいでしょ？これ。キャンバスボードかわいい。
Isn't it cute? This canvas board is so cute.
はい、コメントもりもり上がりへ、わー！(笑)
Let's hear the comment section going wild! Yay! (laughs)
はい、ということで2個目はこちら！
Alright, so the second item is here!
常闇トワモチーフタオル！
Tokoyami Towa motif towel!
ということで、もうくそえも、えもえもえもえも、な、デザイン、お、お、デス、(笑)デザインです。
So, it's very... Very, very, very... cool design!
えー、今日もね、日付も入っておりますので、ぜひぜひあの、チェックしてください！
Today's date is also included on it, so please, please check it out!
ということでラスト行っては、こちら、ポン！
And the last item is here, boom!
ビビのスマホリングとなっております！
BIBI smartphone ring!
え、これ超可愛くない？
Isn't this super cute?
う、可愛いでしょう？
Cu... Cute, right?
はい、これね、あの、スマートフォンにつけてずっとあの、一緒だよ。(笑)
You can attach this to your smartphone and be together with it forever! (laughs)
ずっと一緒だよっていうことで、よろしくね！
You'll always be together, so isn't that nice?
はい、じゃあこのね、3つフルセットを買っていただきますと、ボン！
Alright, if you buy the three-item full set, boom!
はい！ ボン！
タイミングは神すぎる。
The timing is too good.
えーと、えー、じき、えー、違います。え、箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきまーす！
It comes with a duplicate-signed secret message postcard!
えー、数量限定にはなるんですけれども、あの一、サイン、直筆サインもありますので、ぜひぜひゲットしてね！
It comes with the full set, and there's also a hand-signed version, so please definitely get your hands on it!
あー！
Agh!
はい、ということで、えー、1つ目の告知はこちらです！グッズになりましたー！
Alright, so the first announcement is here, the goods are out!
え、概要欄に、えー、貼って、いるので、え、10時ぐらいになったらぱっかーりするんじゃないでしょうか！皆さん、よろしくね！
It will be posted in the description, so once it hits around 10 PM, it'll go live, right? I hope you're all looking forward to it!
はい！
Alright!
ということで、なんとまだあるんです。2つ目は、こちら。
And there's more! The second one is here.
バーン！常闇トワLINEスタンプができますー！
Boom! Tokoyami Towa LINE stickers are finally here!
「おけぴー」とか、「言葉は刃」とか、「メンタルメンタル」とか、え、金太郎とビビとほっぺすりすり！みたいな可愛いスタンプをのいみ先生が描いてくれましたー！
Stickers like "Okay Pee~", "Words are blades", "Mental, mental", "Kintaro and Bibi and Hoppe Suri-Suri" and other cute stickers drawn by Noimi-sensei!
え、これもね、あの、10時ごろには販売されてるんじゃないのでしょうか！ぼぼ。
This will also probably go on sale around 10 PM, right? Bobo.
はい、じゃあぜひこの配信が終わったらチェックしてみてくださいね！
Alright, so please check it out after this stream ends!
はあ、涙を飲み込んで、イェー！
Swallow your tears and go— Yay!
はい！
Alright!
ということで、えー、なんと告知まだあります！3つ目なんとでかいです！
And guess what, there's still more announcements! The third one is huge!
3つ目はこちら、バーン！
The third one is here, boom!
えー、日清焼きそばU.F.O.と常闇トワのコラボが決定ーーー！
Nissin Yakisoba U.F.O. and Tokoyami Towa collaboration is confirmed!
うおおー、どんどん爆笑風コメントも大盛り上がり！
Whoa, tons of expectations and comments are pouring in!
はい、ということで、えー、詳しくはね、1月13日金曜日の11時、え、日清焼きそばU.F.O.公式Twitterをチェックしてください！
Alright, for details, check out the official Nissin Yakisoba U.F.O. Twitter account on Friday, January 13th at 11:00 AM!
うおおー、大盛り上がりです！はい、テーマは悪魔的うまさ感じてみろや。と,s:
Whoa, huge hype! The theme is "Feel the demonic deliciousness!" or something like that.
となっておりまして、はい、内容もりだくさんの企画なのでお楽しみに！今ね、トワも、あの、もうね、準備を準備をしてますので、楽しみに待っててくださーい！
So, it's a project packed with lots of content, so look forward to it! Towa is already making preparations, so please look forward to it!
はーい！
Yay!
ということで、えー、3つ告知をしたが、なんとサプライズであともう1つありまして、
Alright, so I made three announcements, but surprise, there's one more!
なんと新曲があります！
And it's a brand new song!
はい。
Yes.
新曲なんですけれども、作詞作曲編曲はKeinoさんに作っていただきまして、
As for the new song, Keino-san wrote the lyrics, music, and arrangement for me.
まあ、一緒にいりも3年ですから、え、3年経つことは本当にすごいことだと,s:
Well, it's been 3 years since I started, so 3 years passing is truly an amazing thing.
いうことで、トワも今日で3年経ちました！
So today marks 3 years since Towa started!
えー、本当にね、やっぱり、トワ声、声とか、まあ、性格もそうなんだけど、ちょっと自分に自信がないとこがあったんだけど、
Truly, you know, my singing voice and my personality... Well, I sometimes lacked self-confidence, but...
その中でもね、あの、みんなに見つけてもらえて、本当に嬉しかったし、感謝の気持ちがずっとあります。
Even so, you all found me, and I was truly happy, and I've felt continuous gratitude.
で、その、感謝の気持ち見つけてくれてありがとうとか、まあその、感謝の気持ちを、まあ歌詞に乗っけてほしいですと、
And I asked for a song that would say "Thank you for finding that feeling of gratitude," and "expressing that feeling of gratitude."
ご依頼しまして、素敵な、ちょっと恋愛っぽい、曲になっております。
So it turned out to be a wonderful, slightly love-like song.
なのでね、えー、エモい雰囲気で、聞いていただければと思います。
So I hope you'll listen to it with that emotional vibe!
はい。
Yes.
では、えー、ここまで聞いていただき見ていただきありがとうございました！最後1曲、
So, thank you so much for listening and watching up to this point! For the very last song...
えー、心を込めて歌うので、聞いてください。え、サンビタリア。
Please listen to this song filled with my heart, "Sanvitalia".
黙って俯いて
Stay silent and bow down,
空の色さえ知らない私の声で君が笑った
You smiled with my voice, not even knowing the color of the sky.
あの日から世界は眩しくて
Since that day, the world has been dazzling,
私は私を好きになって
I've grown to love myself.
私を 私を好きになって
Loving myself for who I am,
失さないように息をする
I breathe so as not to lose it.
眩むような青空の真ん中で今も
Even now, in the middle of a dazzling blue sky,
泣いているのは
what is crying...
君が映る世界が
is because the world reflecting you
悲しくなるほど優しいから
is so tender it makes me sad.
苦しくなるほど遠いから
And so distant it makes me ache.
じくじくと疼く甘い熱は
The festering, throbbing, sweet fever
閉じ込めていたのに
even though I had locked it away,
痛くて零れた
hurt and spilled over.
君と私の躯と躯の間にある
Between your body and mine,
酷く薄い皮膚さえもう邪魔になるくらい
even this terribly thin skin is becoming a nuisance—
その鼓膜 その心臓 ずっと奥にさわられたら
If that eardrum, that heart, were touched deep within,
君はまだ笑うのかな
would you smile once again?
ねぇどうか君まで届け
Hey, please, reach all the way to you.
強がって笑った
I forced a smile and laughed,
息を呑むような橙の中で
amidst the breathtaking orange glow.
君が見てる世界の隅っこでいいからいさせて
Let me stay in even a corner of the world you see—
どこでもいいから私を見て
Look at me, anywhere is fine.
ねぇ明日は晴れかな雨かななんて
Wondering if tomorrow will be clear or rainy,
そんなこと当たり前に思えるのは君がいたから
being able to take such things for granted was because you were here.
でもね今もこの胸を締め付ける空の色に
But even now, the color of the sky tightening my chest—
立ち尽くしたまま動けないのは
Standing still and unable to move,
頬が濡れていくのは君のせいだ
my cheeks growing wet, it's all because of you.
そんなこと思ってしまったの 思ってしまったんだ
I found myself thinking such things... I really thought them.
私ひとつ分の涙じゃ全然足りないくらいに
Not nearly enough with just a single person's worth of tears—
枯れそうで日び割れて心が止まりそうなの
about to dry up, cracking, my heart feels like it's stopping.
言葉にしようとすればするほど 鳴咽になって溶け出してしまうから
The more I try to put it into words, the more it melts into sobs.
君と私の躯と躯の間にある
Between your body and mine,
呼吸も温度ももう邪魔になるくらい
even breath and warmth are becoming a nuisance—
その鼓膜 その心臓 ずっと奥にさわるから
That eardrum, that heart, touching me deep within,
私を見付けてよ 壊れても叫ぶから
So find me. Even if I break, I will cry out.
ねぇどうか君まで届け
Hey, please, reach all the way to you.
3年間ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for 3 years!
これからも何年も、よろしくね！みんな大好きだよ！
Here's to many more years to come! I love you all so much!
脱ぎ捨てた、ままでよ
Leaving it shed just as it is,
ここに咲く
Blooming right here,
やっと見つけてくれた真夜中
The midnight when you finally found me.
いつか解き放たれた「でも一人じゃ笑えない」
Someday set free, but "I can't smile alone."
瞬く間に 描く導
Drawing the path in the blink of an eye.